Dotan Di Castro

dotan.dicastro@gmail.com • +972(052)8312220 • Married+4 • Haifa District, Israel

Summary

Expertise: AI R&D Managing, Phd in Reinforcement Learning and AI, Roboticist, and AI Expert; Current Role: Group and Lab Manager at Bosch-AI, Haifa, Israel. Research and Impact Manager;

Academics: ~ 910 Google Scholar citations (~ 35 Journal and Conference papers in NeurIPS, ICML, ICRA,

IROS, JMLR, RAL, etc.); **IP:** ~ 30 Patents in US, DE;

Community Service: AC and Reviewer in AI leading conferences.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dotan-di-castro-b0a99039/

Github: https://github.com/dotd

ABOUT

I am a Reinforcement Learning Expert. My main interests are building autonomous systems whether virtual or real (like in manipulation robotics) in the high and low tech industries. I like to apply AI to solve real problems as an individual contributor as well as a manager.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bosch AI Research: Group Manager, Robotics Lab Manager, and Site Manager July 2018 - Present *Mission:* Founded a group for Bosch AI Research. Implemented 3-fold mission of:

- (1) Impact on Bosch products.
- (2) Doing Research
- (3) Building IP Stack

Responsibility: hiring people; establishing research and IP agenda; guiding a group of 15 research scientists, engineers, and interns; Running the lab and site;

Notable projects: RL for Autonomous Dozer | Smart Item Picking using robotic arms | Scheduling using RL | Insertion using robotic arms | Video predictions for 2WP/4WP.

Senior Research Scientist, Yahoo! Labs, Haifa, Israel

2013 - 2018

Working mainly in Yahoo Mail and Ads products. Technical lead of Automatic Extraction.

CTO Modana (Startup)

2012 - 2013

Role: Modana developed a context aware product for mobile sensing using the smartphone.

Research Scientist, Pulsar Investments Inc.

2009 - 2012

Role: Research scientist in an algorithmic trading startup. Main market: CME.

IBM Research

2000 - 2004

Student Apprentice

EDUCATION

Postdoc in EE, Technion, Israel

2010 - 2011

Host: Prof. Shie Mannor

PhD in EE, Technion, Israel

2006 - 2010

Thesis: Aspects of Actor-Critic Algorithms: Theory and Experiments. Advisor: Prof. Ron Meir

MSc in EE, Technion, Israel

2004 - 2006

Thesis: Population Behavior of Neural Networks. Advisor: Prof. Ron Meir

BSc in EE, Technion, Israel

2004 - 2006

Cum Laude

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages (Proficient): Python, Java, Scala
- Deep Learning frameworks: PyTorch, Keras
- Big Data frameworks: Spark, Hadoop, Docker